# JASON NESTER

jayleedesigns@gmail.com 330.937.2206 http://www.jasonnester.com

#### MULTIMEDIA & UX DESIGN PROFESSIONAL

# Summary

I am a hardworking guy with a comprehensive knowledge of web and multimedia technologies from Northeast Ohio. I like to create colorful and dynamic media that engages and entertains. I have over 14 years experience in web design and over 18 in art and traditional illustration. I have worked at several big creative agencies as well as Kent State University as An Educational Technologies Designer. I have a wide skill set including but not limited to, graphic design, illustration, character design, branding, motion graphics and web design and development, as well as mobile app and game development.

I am looking for opportunities in Graphic Design and Front-End Development.

## Experience

# Kent State University Multimedia Developer

07 / 2009 - 11 / 2015

Led a team of designers and developers to transform student and faculty needs into functional product design to support the Office of the Provost's online course distribution initiative. Improved the usability, usefulness, and desirability of in-house Educational Technology Applications, referred to as ET-Apps. Provided graphics and communication work for student focused marketing initiatives as well as the look and feel of the Information Services Tech Help rebrand.

In addition to this I also provided the front-end development for many of the essential

web based tools and campaigns related to both coursework and grant based programs. Notable Development projects include:

Media Power & Culture [http://mpc.kent.edu] JMC Ethics conferences [mediaethics.jmc.kent.edu/] Information Services [http://www.kent.edu/is] KSUtube [https://ksutube.kent.edu/] Presenter [https://presenter.kent.edu/] KSU Dropbox [https://dropbox.kent.edu/home.cfm]

### PixelNaut Game Studios LLC Owner

12 / 2012 - 10 / 2015

Through my Company I have aided in and created over 200 games and applications for platforms such as iOS, Android, Kindle and Tizen. I have used may different sdks and languages when developing, but I primarily focus on the interface design and production. Some clients include MTV, Sony Pictures and Comfort Suites.

IdeaStar

09 / 2008 - 03 / 2009

Creative & Interactive Designer

My responsibilities were to develop graphic design for web, print, and video HTML/XHTML and CSS breakouts for web application Flash design and development

# Renaissance Marketing Group Creative Designer

2005 - 2009

Created in house graphics as well as web development. I also provided graphics and multimedia solutions for RMG's numerous clients.

### True Media Games

05 / 2007 - 12 / 2008

Owner/ Lead Developer and Designer

True Media Games is a small independent games company, with a focus on the casual market, developing titles for iPad, iPhone, iPod Touch as well as the Android and HTML5 platforms.

## One Business Builders Resources Lead Designer

04 / 2005 - 10 / 2008

In this position, I was responsible for coming up with creative design concepts for clients. I still do much of this companies design work, or at least establish the base of many of the current projects.

# Centric Technologies Group

09 / 2007 - 09 / 2008

Creative Communications Director

I was the lead designer/ developer for Centric Technologies and It's three sub companies, doing all the print. web and graphic design. Developing the brands and executing the marketing communications concerning them as well. (A2Z Computers, PCHardware4U, Exactfix Computer Solutions)

### Education

# Stanford University

2014 - 2014

# Certificate , Human Computer Interaction

2003 - 2006

Art Institute of Pittsburgh Bachelor's degree , Graphic Design

The Industrial Design Annual Haunted House Committee

# Aurora High School

1999 - 2003

Diploma, High School/Secondary Diplomas and Certificates

Show Choir, Cross Country, Football, AP Art.

New Horizons Computer Learning School

2001 - 2002

#### Skills • User Experience • Graphic Design • Web Design Flash CSS • Multimedia • Illustration • Mobile Applications • Illustrator • Photoshop • Game Design • User Interface Design • PHP • Game Development • HTML WordPress · Video Editing • Interaction Design • Joomla • Logo Design • HTML 5 After Effects • Mobile Game • osCommerce Development • User Experience • Character Animation • Video Design • CMS · Branding & Identity • SEO Dreamweaver jQuery • ActionScript • XHTML Information Architecture • Website Development • Art Direction • Web Applications • Layout • Character Design • UX Design

• iPhone Application • LESS

Certifications

A+ CompTIA

Design

07 / 2002

SASS

## Cisco Certified Network Associate Cisco

08 / 2002

### Honors

I have worked on several projects in collaboration with many talented people. One such project was Media Power and Culture for Kent State's Gary Hanson and Ben Hollis. It has won quite a few awards:

BEA Best of Festival King Foundation Award 2011

AEJMC Best of the Web Third place for team innovation -  $2010\,$ 

Portage County Arts Show • I received both first and second place in the Watercolor category for portraiture. 2003 2003 Scholastic Arts Show • I received a gold key for a portrait rendition in watercolor. • I also received the shows highest honor, a gold key for my 12 piece portfolio, which then went on to national competition. 2003 Business Professionals of America • I placed second in my region for web design at the Business Professionals of America.